# Hyunsik Jeon

Postdoctoral Researcher ⋄ CSE, UC San Diego Room 4202 ⋄ CSE Department

Email: hyjeon@ucsd.edu \leftharpoonup Homepage: https://jeon185.github.io

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research aims to empower personalization in various web services through Artificial Intelligence (AI). My current research focuses on fair and accurate conversational recommender systems exploiting Large Language Models' (LLMs) ability.

I am broadly interested in data mining and applied machine learning:

#### Recommender Systems

Domains: IoT (CIKM'22), news (PAKDD'20, KAIS'21), and bundle (PLOS ONE'23)

Metrics: diversity (PAKDD'23, PAKDD'23) and explainability (Arxiv'17)

Settings: cold-start (WWW'24) and additional information utilization (BigData'19)

## Graph Learning

Node-feature estimation (KDD'22) and semi-supervised learning (IJCAI'19)

# Transfer Learning

Multi-source domain adaptation (PLOS ONE'21, PLOS ONE'21)

#### **POSITION**

# University of California San Diego, CA, USA

Sep. 2023 - Present

Postdoctoral Researcher, Computer Science & Engineering

Advisor: Prof. Julian McAuley

#### **EDUCATION**

# Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

Aug. 2023

Ph.D., Computer Science & Engineering

Thesis: "Modeling Bundle Recommendation with Personalized Pattern Analysis"

Distinguished Ph.D. Dissertation Award

Advisor: Prof. U Kang

# Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

Feb. 2019

M.Sc., Computer Science & Engineering

Thesis: "Context Adaptation for Accurate Recommendation with Collective Matrix Factorization"

Advisor: Prof. U Kang

## Hanyang University, Seoul, South Korea

Feb. 2017

B.Sc., Computer Science & Engineering

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

# Hyperconnect, Seoul, South Korea

Jul. 2020 - Aug. 2020

Research Intern, Machine Learning Group

#### AWARDS AND HONORS

#### Distinguished Ph.D. Dissertation Award

Aug. 2023

Dept. of CSE at Seoul National University

#### Sejong Science Fellowship Grants (Overseas Training Track)

May. 2023

Funding for 2 years of Postdoctoral Research, National Research Foundation of Korea

Topic: "Accurate, Robust, and Interactive Recommender Systems for Enhancing User Experience"

## **SIGIR Student Travel Grants**

Aug. 2022

ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM), 2022, Atlanta, USA

MIND News Recommendation Competition Award

Microsoft Research

Second Prize Award (215 teams participated)

Best Student Paper Award

May. 2020

Sep. 2020

Pacific-Asia Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (PAKDD), 2020, Singapore

HumanTech Paper Award

Feb. 2020

Samsung Electronics

Honorable Mention - 4th in CSE

**BigData Student Travel Grants** 

Dec. 2019

IEEE International Conference on Big Data (BigData), 2019, Los Angeles, USA

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

#### Refereed conferences

C8. Cold-start Bundle Recommendation via Popularity-based Coalescence and Curriculum Heating Hyunsik Jeon, Jong-eun Lee, Jeongin Yun, and U Kang

ACM The Web Conference (WWW), 2024, Singapore

Oral Presentation:  $189/2008 \approx 9.4\%$  - Acceptance Rate:  $405/2008 \approx 20.2\%$ 

C7. Aggregately Diversified Bundle Recommendation via Popularity Debiasing and Configuration-aware Reranking

Hyunsik Jeon, Jongjin Kim, Jaeri Lee, Jong-eun Lee, and U Kang

Pacific-Asia Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (PAKDD), 2023, Osaka, Japan Oral Presentation - Acceptance Rate:  $143/822 \approx 17.4\%$ 

C6. Diversely Regularized Matrix Factorization for Accurate and Aggregately Diversified Recommendation Jongjin Kim, Hyunsik Jeon, Jaeri Lee, and U Kang

Pacific-Asia Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (PAKDD), 2023, Osaka, Japan Oral Presentation - Acceptance Rate:  $143/822 \approx 17.4\%$ 

C5. Accurate Action Recommendation for Smart Home via Two-Level Encoders and Commonsense Knowledge Hyunsik Jeon, Jongjin Kim, Hoyoung Yoon, Jaeri Lee, and U Kang

ACM International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM), 2022, Atlanta, USA Oral Presentation - Acceptance Rate:  $274/1175 \approx 23.2\%$ 

C4. Accurate Node Feature Estimation with Structured Variational Graph Autoencoder Jaemin Yoo, Hyunsik Jeon, Jinhong Jung, and U Kang

ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD), 2022, Washington DC, USA Oral Presentation - Acceptance Rate:  $254/1695 \approx 15.0\%$ 

C3. Accurate News Recommendation Coalescing Personal and Global Temporal Preferences Bonhun Koo, Hyunsik Jeon, and U Kang

Pacific-Asia Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (PAKDD), 2020, Singapore Oral Presentation - Acceptance Rate:  $135/628 \approx 21.5\%$ 

Best Student Paper Award

C2. Data Context Adaptation for Accurate Recommendation with Additional Information

Hyunsik Jeon, Bonhun Koo, and U Kang

IEEE International Conference on Big Data (BigData), 2019, Los Angeles, USA Oral Presentation - Acceptance Rate:  $106/550 \approx 19.3\%$ 

Samsung HumanTech Paper Award

C1. Belief Propagation Network for Hard Inductive Semi-supervised Learning

Jaemin Yoo, Hyunsik Jeon, and U Kang

International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2019, Macao, China Oral Presentation - Acceptance Rate:  $850/4752 \approx 17.9\%$ 

## Refereed journals

- J4. Accurate Bundle Matching and Generation via Multitask Learning with Partially Shared Parameters Hyunsik Jeon, Jun-Gi Jang, Taehun Kim, and U Kang PLOS ONE. 2023
- J3. PGT: News Recommendation Coalescing Personal and Global Temporal Preferences Bonhun Koo, <u>Hyunsik Jeon</u>, and U Kang Knowledge and Information Systems (KAIS), 2021
- J2. Multi-EPL: Accurate Multi-Source Domain Adaptation Seongmin Lee, <u>Hyunsik Jeon</u>, and U Kang **PLOS ONE**, 2021
- J1. Unsupervised Multi-Source Domain Adaptation with No Observable Source Data Hyunsik Jeon, Seongmin Lee, and U Kang PLOS ONE, 2021

#### Others

O1. UniWalk: Explainable and Accurate Recommendation for Rating and Network Data Haekyu Park, <u>Hyunsik Jeon</u>, Junghwan Kim, Beunguk Ahn, and U Kang **arXiv**:1710.07134, 2017

#### **PATENTS**

#### Korea

- P6. Apparatus and Method for Recommending Bundled Items Hyunsik Jeon, Jongjin Kim, Jaeri Lee, Jong-eun Lee, and U Kang (filed on Nov. 2022)
- P5. Method and Apparatus for Recommending Items Based on Diversely Regularized Matrix Factorization Jongjin Kim, Hyunsik Jeon, Jaeri Lee, and U Kang (filed on Nov. 2022)
- P4. Electronic Device and Computer Readable Storage Medimum for Control Recommendation <u>Hyunsik Jeon</u>, Jongjin Kim, Hoyoung Yoon, Jaeri Lee, Hyunju Seo, Sanghee Kim, Inchul Hwang, and U <u>Kang (filed on Aug. 2022)</u>
- P3. Apparatus and Method for Predicting Feature of Node Jaemin Yoo, <u>Hyunsik Jeon</u>, Jinhong Jung, and U Kang (filed on Dec. 2021)
- P2. Apparatus and Method for Unsupervised Domain Adaptation Hyunsik Jeon, Seongmin Lee, and U Kang (filed on Oct. 2021)
- P1. Explainable and Accurate Recommender Method and System Using Social Network Information and Rating Information

Haekyu Park, Hyunsik Jeon, and Junghwan Kim, and U Kang (filed on Nov. 2017)

#### PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

Program Committee	
IEEE International Conference on Big Data and Smart Computing (BigComp)	2021 - 2023
SIAM International Conference on Data Mining (SDM)	2024
Reviewer	
IEEE International Conference on Big Data and Smart Computing (BigComp)	2020
ACM International Conference on Information Management (CIKM)	2018 - 2019
IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)	2019
International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)	2021
ACM SIGKDD Conference of Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD)	2019 - 2024
Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)	2021 - 2023
The Web Conference (formerly WWW)	2019 - 2021, 2024
ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining (WSDM)	2019
Frontiers in Big Data	2023 - 2024

#### INVITED TALKS

# Academia

Jul. 4, 2023
Dec. 21, 2022
Dec. 19, 2019

# TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Seoul National University	
T.A., Undergraduate Research Opportunities Program (UROP) @ SNU	2017, 2020, 2022
T.A., M2177.004900: Theory and Lab of IoT, AI, and Big Data @ SNU	$Spring \ 2019$
T.A., 4190.773: Optimization for Machine Learning (Topics in Artificial Intelligence) @ SNU	$Spring \ 2018$
<b>T.A.</b> , M1522.000900: Data Structure @ SNU	Fall 2017
Other Organizations	
T.A., Advanced DS @ LG	2023
T.A., AI Master @ Hyundai Motors	2022
T.A., AI Lectures @ KDB	2022 - 2023
T.A., SK-Univ @ SK	2020
T.A., DS Advanced Projects @ LG	2020
T.A., DxP (1st) @ Hana Financial Group	2019
T.A., AI Action Learning @ Samsung Electronics	2019
T.A., NPEX (1st - 2nd) @ Samsung Electronics	2019 - 2020
$\mathbf{T.A.}$ , $\mathrm{DS}^2$ (3rd - 9th) @ Samsung Electronics	2019 - 2022

# PROJECTS

Elancer, Job Matching	2023
Samsung C-Lab, Plan Recommender Systems	2023
JungHun Foundation, Recommender Systems Under Constraints	2022
Samsung, Effective Expression and Compression of Knowledge-Base for IoT Devices	2022
Posco-ICT, Recommender Systems for Learning Platform	2022
JungHun Foundation, Recommender Systems Under Constraints	2021
Samsung, Data Driven Analysis and Reasoning for Device Control	2021
LINA, Prediction and Control of Insurance Cancellation	2020
Wemakeprice, Recommender Systems Based on Deep Learning	2019
LG, Failure Detection for Compressor in Refrigerator	2018
LG, Optimization of Sputtering for Uniform Film Formation	2018
SKT, Feature Selection for RNN-based Recommender Systems	2018
SKT, Recommender Systems for Oksusu Videos	2017

# REFERENCES

Prof. Julian McAuley (Postdoc advisor) - University of California, San Diego	jmcauley@eng.ucsd.edu
Prof. U Kang (PhD advisor) - Seoul National University	ukang@snu.ac.kr